Muhammad Tayyab Rafique

Senior Full Stack Developer (More than 6 years Experience)

Linkedin Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tayyab-rafique-9719b7142

Email: tayyabrafique436@gmail.com Cell: +92332-8602674

Address: House# 33 Street# 11 Hassan Town DOB: 27-April-1992

Multan Road Lahore, Pakistan.

PERSONAL STATEMENT (SUMMARY)

I am a graduate in computer science. I have been working on web applications and databases for **more than 6 years**. My expertise is development of **highly scalable applications** using Object Oriented Design , docker and kubernetes. My salient technical skills are PHP, Javascript, Node, React, MySQL, Mongo, Docker and Kubernetes. Moreover, I have adequate working knowledge on **Linux servers** , **Amazon web services and Digital Ocean**.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (More than 6 Years)

(Jan 2021 - Current) TECHFOOT, PAKISTAN

Senior Software Engineer (Full Stack)

My contribution is on a billing application which is designed as a microservices architecture. The primary goal of this application is to process utility bills. The detail of the technology stack are as follows.

- Working as a Full Stack Developer (**Node JS**)
- Amazon Web Services
- Docker & Kubernetes for Application Scaling
- o Node API
- o TypeORM
- o Agile Model & JIRA
- o Git & GitHub

(July 2017 – Jan 2021) NETSOL TECHNOLOGIES INC, PAKISTAN

Senior Software Engineer (LAMP STACK & JAVASCRIPT)

- Worked as a Backend Web Application Developer
- o Experience of Linux servers Ubuntu, Centos7
- o Amazon Web Services
- Worked on Third Party API Integration
- Concurrency Control
- Payment Integration CCAvenue (Dubai)
- Yii2 Framework, Javascript, Twig Templating Engine, Codeigniter 3, Angular js
- o Agile Model
- o Jira Environment
- SVN version control
- Object Oriented Model
- Algorithm design and Implementation
- Startup Projects
- Specially working on International Hotels booking API integration like HotelBeds, GTA,
 Zumata, Bookingee etc.

(Dec 2015 – June 2017) NASEEB ONLINE SERVICES PVT LIMITED (ROZEE.PK), PAKISTAN

Software Engineer

- Worked as a Backend Web Application Developer
- Worked on Revamp overall rozee.pk.
- o Revamp overall mahnati.com
- Object Oriented Design
- o Requirement analysis
- o Features Enhancement
- Algorithm Implementation
- o Javascript, NAS Framework, Twig Templating Engine
- o Link: https://www.rozee.pk
- Link: https://www.mihnati.com (Saudi-Arabia)

(Oct 2015 – Dec 2015) CHECKIN.PK, PAKISTAN

Associate Software Engineer

- o Worked on online Air Ticketing System
- o Sabre APIS
- o Laravel 5 Framework, Angular js, Javascript
- o Link: https://www.checkin.pk

Skills:

Development Skills

o HTML

- o CSS
- o Bootstrap
- Javascript
- o Node Js
- o React Js
- o Next Js
- o PHP
- o Database Design
- Mysql
- o Mongo
- o TypeORM
- o Git

DevOps Skills

- o Linux Servers
- o AWS Web Services
- o Digital Ocean
- o Docker
- o Kubernetes
- Monitoring
- Fluentd Logging
- o Nginx Management
- o PM2 Management

EDUCATION

2011–2015 Lahore Leads UNIVERSITY, Pakistan

BS (Hons) Computer Science (CGPA 3.26)

2009 - 2011 Mansoora Model Degree College

F.Sc Pre Engineering (Grade A+)

2006 - 2008 Govt.High School Allama Iqbal Town Lahore

Secondary School Education (Grade A+)

AWARDS AND HONORS

- President of computer science society
- Cash Prize winning in university IT quiz competition
- Certificate for completion of Oracle 11g workshop

Personal Interest

- Books Reading
- Cricket
- Football
- Table Tennis
- Open Discussion

References

References will be available on demand.